interworks.com 2019-12-09

# Privacy Policy | InterWorks

## Introduction

InterWorks is a global consulting firm, including its affiliates, (collectively, “InterWorks”, “us,” “our,” or “we”) that provides con­sulting services and related products to help clients solve technology problems. At InterWorks, the privacy and security of our clients and visitors are of paramount importance. This Privacy Policy explains how we process information that can be used to directly or indirectly identify an individual (“Personal Data”) collected through use of our website, and/or any of our other sites, products, or services that link to this Privacy Policy, specifically when InterWorks is acting as a data controller in relation to your Personal Data. We use cookies on our website, and we will ask you to consent to our use of cookies when you first visit our website. For more information on cookies, see “Cookies And Other Tracking Methods” below. By using our website, you understand and consent that we will collect and use your information as described in this Privacy Policy.

## CATEGORIES OF PERSONAL DATA

Listed below are the are the different categories of Personal Data that we may collect and process, the purposes that we may process each category, and the legal bases for the processing. Each of the following categories is considered Personal Data.

### Usage Data

We may process data related to the use of our website and services (“Usage Data”), including your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths, information about the timing, frequency and patterns of your use. Usage Data is collected by our website tracking system, and is used for analyzing the use of our website, improving its functionality, and optimizing your website experience. The legal basis for processing Usage Data is the consent you give when you visit our website, as well as our legitimate business interest in monitoring and improving our website and services.

### Relationship Data

We may process data related to our relationship with you (“Relationship Data”), including your first and last name, your postal and email address, your telephone number, your job title, data for social networks, your areas of interest, interest in our services and products, and certain information about your employer (company name and address), as well as information as to the type of relationship that exists between InterWorks and yourself. Relationship Data is collected from directly from you or your employer and is used for the purpose of managing our relationship with you, communication and marketing regarding our services, maintaining records of our communications with you. The legal basis for processing Relationship Data is by your consent, as well as our legitimate business interest in maintaining good business relationships and proper administration of our business.

### Event Registration Data

We may process data you provide us when you choose to register for an event that is organized or promoted by InterWorks or one of our partners (“Event Registration Data”). Event Registration Data is collected by website forms, and is used for organizing, promoting, and carrying out business events, and may be shared with our partners or co-sponsors of the event. The legal basis for processing Event Registration Data is your consent when registering for the event.

### Transaction Data

We may process data from purchases of goods and/or services that you make through our website (“Transaction Data”), including your contact information, your card details and the transaction details. Transaction Data is collected by website forms through a third-party system, Authorize.Net, and is processed to supply and provide further information about the purchased goods and/or services and to keep records of the transaction(s). The legal basis for processing Transaction Data is the performance of a sale contract between you and us.

### Service Request Data

We may process data you provide when you request online service and assistance (“Service Request Data”). Service Request Data is collected by website forms through a third-party system, SolarWinds MSP, and is processed to fulfill the service request and provide technical assistance to you. The legal basis for processing Service Request Data is the performance of a service contract between you and us.

### Job Application Data

We may process data you provide us when applying for job with InterWorks (“Job Application Data”), including your first and last name, your postal and email address, your telephone number, your career and education history, your social media profiles, your criminal history, personal references, and work authorization status. Job Application Data is collected by website forms through a third-party system, JazzHR, and is used to process job applications for our hiring process. The legal basis for processing Job Application Data is your consent in applying for a job with InterWorks, and our legitimate interest in proper administration of our business.

## DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL DATA TO THIRD PARTIES

We may disclose or transfer your Personal Data to certain third-parties, as more fully described in this section. When we make such disclosures, we seek contractual assurances as to the security of your data in accordance with this Privacy Policy and applicable laws.

We may disclose Personal Data to any of our affiliated companies, including companies under common control and independently owned companies operating under the InterWorks name) when reasonably necessary for the purposes, and on the same legal bases, set out in this Privacy Policy. You can learn more about our affiliated companies in the “About InterWorks” section below.

We may disclose Personal Data to our insurers or professional advisers (including, but not limited to, accountants and attorneys) when reasonably necessary to maintain insurance coverage, manage risks, obtain professional advice, or to aid in legal claims or defenses, whether in a court or other negotiation, mediation, or arbitration proceeding.

We may disclose Relationship Data to our suppliers or subcontractors only when reasonably necessary to fulfill contracts to provide products or services to you.

Financial transactions relating to our website and services are currently handled by our payment services provider, Authorize.Net. We share Transaction Data with Authorize.Net only to the extent necessary to process your payment(s), refunding such payment(s), and dealing with inquiries related to such payment(s). You can find information about Authorize.Net’s privacy policies and practices at: https://www.authorize.net/company/privacy.

Online technical assistance services are currently handled through our online services provider, SolarWinds MSP. We share Service Request Data with SolarWinds MSP only to the extent necessary to provide the requested online technical assistance to you. You can find information about SolarWindsMSP’s privacy policies and practices at: https://www.solarwindsmsp.com/legal/privacy.

Job application processing is currently handled by our HR processing provider, JazzHR. We share Job Application Data with JazzHR only to the extent necessary to process your job application. You can find information about JazzHR’s privacy policies and practices at: https://www.jazzhr.com/privacy-policy.

We may disclose Relationship Data or Event Registration Date to one or more of our third-party partners (listed at: https://interworks.com/community/partners) so that they can offer, market, and sell relevant goods and services. Each such third-party partner will act as a data controller of the Personal Data that we supply to it, and each such third-party partner will provide you with its own privacy policy, which will govern that third-party partner’s use of your Personal Data.

We may disclose your Personal Data when necessary to comply with our legal obligations or to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another person.

## Encryption & Security

We use various technical and organizational security measures, including encryption and authentication tools, to protect your Personal Data. Your Personal Data is stored in secured networks with limited accessibility by our employees with special access rights to these systems. However, no environment is completely secure or error-free, and even the most secure systems may be subject to compromise. You acknowledge that we cannot be held responsible for unauthorized or unintended access that is beyond our control.

## International transfers of your personal data

We may transfer, process, and store your Personal Data outside of your home country, including in the United States and Canada, which may not have the same level of data protection as your home country. For the avoidance of doubt, if you are resident in the European Economic Area (“EEA”) or Switzerland, this may include the transfer of your personal information from within the EEA or Switzerland to a country outside of the EEA or Switzerland. Nevertheless, when we transfer your Personal Data to recipients in other countries, including the United States, we will protect that Personal Data as described in this Privacy Policy and in compliance with applicable law. If you are in the EEA or Switzerland, we take measures to comply with applicable legal requirements and ensure adequate protection for the transfer of Personal Data to recipients in countries outside of the EEA or Switzerland.

## Retaining and deleting personal data

Personal Data that we process for any purpose or purposes shall not be kept for longer than is necessary for that purpose or those purposes, except as required by applicable law. We may retain your Personal Data when necessary for a legal obligation, or to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another person.

## Changes to this privacy policy

This Privacy Policy may be updated or changed from time to time. All updates will be posted on our website. If we materially change the way in which we use Personal Data, we will provide you with prior notice, or where legally required, request your consent prior to implementing such changes. We strongly encourage you to read this Privacy Policy and keep yourself informed of our practices.

## Your rights

You have the following rights in relation to your Personal Data: the right to access your data; the right to correction of inaccurate or incomplete data; the right to deletion of your data; the right to restrict processing; the right to object to processing; the right to data portability; the right to complain to a supervisory authority; and the right to withdraw your prior consent.

You may request to know if we process your Personal Data and, if we do, you may also request details on how your Personal Data is used and who else may have access to your data. If you object, or withdraw your prior consent, to the use of your Personal Data for direct marketing purposes, we will not use your data for such purposes. You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. We will provide a copy of your personal data upon your request. You may also request the deletion of your Personal Data, except where we are required to retain the data under applicable law.

If you would like to exercise any of these rights, or have other questions about our use of your Personal Data, please contact: InterWorks, Attn: Data Privacy, 1425 S. Sangre Rd., Stillwater, OK, 74074; dataprivacy@interworks.com

## Your California privacy rights

Under California’s “Shine the Light” law, California residents who provide personal information in obtaining products or services for personal, family or household use are entitled to request and obtain from us once a calendar year information about the customer information we shared, if any, with other businesses for their own direct marketing uses. If applicable, this information would include the categories of customer information and the names and addresses of those businesses with which we shared customer information for the immediately prior calendar year. To obtain this information, please send an email message to dataprivacy@interworks.com with “Request for California Privacy Information” on the subject line and in the body of your message. We will provide the requested information to you at your e-mail address in response. Please be aware that not all information sharing is covered by the “Shine the Light” requirements and only information on covered sharing will be included in our response.

## Children

The InterWorks website is not structured for children. We do not knowingly collect Personal Data from anyone under 13 years of age.

## Cookies and OTHER Tracking methods

A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers downloaded on to a device when the user accesses certain websites. Cookies cannot harm your computer – they are not viruses and they can be deleted easily at any point in your browser settings. Cookies allow a website to recognize a user’s device. Other tracking methods operate much like cookies. They allow the website to recognize your device from those of other visitors. More information about cookies and other tracking technologies is available at www.allaboutcookies.org and www.youronlinechoices.eu.

### How we use cookies

We use cookies for the following purposes:

  * to identify you when you visit our website and as you navigate our website
  * to help us to determine if you are logged into our website
  * to store information about your preferences and to personalize the website for you
  * as an element of the security measures used to protect user accounts, including preventing fraudulent use of login credentials, and to protect our website and services generally
  * to help us to analyze the use and performance of our website and services
  * to store your preferences in relation to the use of cookies more generally

### How our service providers use cookies

We use Google Analytics to analyze the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages visited. [Learn more about how Google Analytics uses cookies](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245).  You can choose to [opt out of Google Analytics](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

We use Pardot as part of our marketing automation system. Pardot sets cookies for tracking purposes and do not store personally identifying information; they store only a unique identifier. [Learn more about Pardot cookies](https://help.salesforce.com/articleView?id=pardot_basics_cookies.htm&type=5).

We use Disqus as a discussion platform for comments on our blogs. If you comment on our site through your Disqus account, Disqus will set tracking cookies. [Learn more about Disqus cookies](https://help.disqus.com/user-profile/use-of-cookies).

We use the CloudFlare service to identify trusted web traffic. The CloudFlare cookie does not correspond to any user id in the web application, nor does the cookie store any personally identifiable information. [Learn more about the CloudFlare cookie](https://support.cloudflare.com/hc/en-us/articles/200170156-What-does-the-CloudFlare-cfduid-cookie-do-).

### Managing cookies

Most browsers allow you to modify your preferences for how cookies are used. You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies, by adjusting your browser’s settings. Each browser is different, so look at your browser Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies. If you block cookies, you will not be able to use all the features on our website. Similarly, you can adjust your advertising preferences on your mobile device at the device level.  For example, to adjust your advertising preferences in iOS, visit Settings > Privacy > Advertising > Limit Ad Tracking. To adjust your advertising preferences in Android, visit Settings > Google > Ads > Opt out of interest-based ads.

## About InterWorks

This website is owned and operated by InterWorks, Inc., an Oklahoma corporation with a principal place of business at 1425 S. Sangre Rd., Stillwater, OK, 74074.

### Affiliated companies

Operations in Europe are conducted through InterWorks Europe Ltd., registered in England and Wales under registration number 08368863, and its subsidiary InterWorks GmbH, Registerblatt HRB 79752. InterWorks Europe Ltd. is an independent company operating under license from InterWorks, Inc. Operations in Asia and Australia are conducted through InterWorks APAC Pty. Ltd., a Singapore company with registration number 201735870K, and its subsidiary InterWorks AUS Pte. Ltd, ABN 52 623 423 352, an Australian company. InterWorks APAC Pty. Ltd. is a company under common control with InterWorks, Inc.

### Data protection officer

The data protection officer for InterWorks and all affiliated companied can be reached at:

InterWorks  
ATTN: Data Protection Officer  
1425 South Sangre Road  
Stillwater, Oklahoma 74074  
[dataprivacy@interworks.com  
](mailto:dataprivacy@interworks.com)(405) 624-3214
